<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quantitative Finance on Mark Aron Szulyovszky</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quantitative-finance/</link><description>Recent content in Quantitative Finance on Mark Aron Szulyovszky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quantitative-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alpha vs beta</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quantitative-finance/alpha-vs-beta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quantitative-finance/alpha-vs-beta/</guid><description>Alpha vs beta Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the definitions:
Alpha Excess returns you gain over the market.
Only available to you. Requires you to have an edge (information that&amp;rsquo;s not baked into the price already). Zero-sum game. If you gain, somebody loses. Short-lived. As soon as the market finds about your edge, it&amp;rsquo;ll arbitrage it away. As a retail (non-institunioal) investor, your alpha (edge) sources are limited. Anything well-known is probably arbitraged away already (if it can be), by the time the info reaches you.</description></item><item><title>The reasons against discretionary (non-systematic) investing (like stock picking, etc)</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quantitative-finance/the-reasons-against-discretionary-investing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quantitative-finance/the-reasons-against-discretionary-investing/</guid><description>The reasons against discretionary (non-systematic) investing (like stock picking, etc) 1. As a retail investor (with fees against you, and being an outsider), you have no obvious edge over the market.
2. If something seems under- or overpriced to you, you probably don’t have all the info, and the market is most probably right.
3. Even if your views are correct, there’s a huge amount of uncertainty in the future, that’s not connected to you being right or wrong, which can result in a much larger impact on your bet / investment - aka your edge may only play a very small role in your positive or negative returns.</description></item></channel></rss>