<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>(Quantitative) Finance / Investment on Mark Aron Szulyovszky</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/</link><description>Recent content in (Quantitative) Finance / Investment on Mark Aron Szulyovszky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alpha vs beta</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/alpha-vs-beta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/alpha-vs-beta/</guid><description>Alpha vs beta Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the definitions:
Alpha Excess returns you gain over the market.
Only available to you. Requires you to have an edge (information that&amp;rsquo;s not baked into the price already). Zero-sum game. If you gain, somebody loses. Short-lived. As soon as the market finds about your edge, it&amp;rsquo;ll arbitrage it away. As a retail (non-institunioal) investor, your alpha (edge) sources are limited. Anything well-known is probably arbitraged away already (if it can be), by the time the info reaches you.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Tactical Asset Allocation</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/intro-to-tactical-asset-allocation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/intro-to-tactical-asset-allocation/</guid><description>Intro to Tactical Asset Allocation Concept Have a semi-active portfolio that you can invest in that outperforms the 60-40 (60% Stock, 40% bond) static portfolio over the long run with a reduced maximum loss.
Investing in an index fund (eg. the S&amp;amp;P 500) is the “standard” passive strategy people use, but those who do that experienced a 50% loss of their capital in the last 20 year multiple times. Depending on when you invest, your balance could be negative for 10 years.</description></item><item><title>The reasons against stock picking</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/the-reasons-against-stock-picking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/the-reasons-against-stock-picking/</guid><description>The reasons against stock picking 1. As a retail investor (with fees against you, and being an outsider), you have no obvious edge over the market. Everything that’s in the mainstream financial press is most probably baked into the price.
2. If something seems under- or overpriced to you, you probably don’t have all the info, and the market is most probably right.
3. Even if your views are correct, there’s a huge amount of uncertainty in the future, that’s not connected to you being right or wrong, which can result in a much larger impact on your bet / investment - aka your edge may only play a very small role in your positive or negative returns.</description></item></channel></rss>