<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>(Quantitative) Finance / Investment on Mark Aron Szulyovszky</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/</link><description>Recent content in (Quantitative) Finance / Investment on Mark Aron Szulyovszky</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Recommendations</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/books/</guid><description>Book recommendations Joachim Klement: 7 Mistakes Every Investor Makes (and How to Avoid Them): A Manifesto for Smarter Investing
A great summary about how investors deceive themselves. Repeating a Goodreads review: An honest investment self help book that doesn&amp;rsquo;t read like a normal self help book. No secrets, magic recipes but rather logical advice backed by research and data. Highly recommended for both private and professional investors.
Gary Antonacci: Dual Momentum Investing</description></item><item><title>Concept: Volatility Drag</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/volatility-drag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/volatility-drag/</guid><description>Volatility Drag If you lose 50% of your capital in one year, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to achieve a 100% return the next year, just to get even. This asymmetry is the cause of the &amp;ldquo;Volatility drag&amp;rdquo; - one unit loss will hurt your long-term gains more than one unit gain.
This reason why you want to optimize your portfolio to avoid losses on your capital, rather for extraordinary gains.
The volatility drag could potentially explain the low-volatility anomaly</description></item><item><title>Concepts: Alpha vs Beta?</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/alpha-vs-beta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/alpha-vs-beta/</guid><description>Alpha vs beta Alpha Excess returns you gain over the market.
Only available to you. Requires you to have an edge (information that&amp;rsquo;s not baked into the price already). Zero-sum game. If you gain, somebody loses. Short-lived. As soon as the market finds about your edge, it&amp;rsquo;ll arbitrage it away. As a retail (non-institunioal) investor, your alpha (edge) sources are limited. Anything well-known is probably arbitraged away already (if it can be), by the time the info reaches you.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Tactical Asset Allocation</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/intro-to-tactical-asset-allocation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/intro-to-tactical-asset-allocation/</guid><description>Intro to Tactical Asset Allocation Concept Have a semi-active portfolio that you can invest in that outperforms the 60-40 (60% Stock, 40% bond) static portfolio over the long run with a reduced maximum loss, by dynamically changing the allocated percentages monthly.
Investing in an index fund (eg. the S&amp;amp;P 500) is the “standard” passive strategy people use, but those who have done that experienced a 50% loss of their capital in the last 20 year multiple times.</description></item><item><title>The reasons against discretionary investing</title><link>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/the-reasons-against-discretionary-investing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itchingpixels.com/docs/quant/the-reasons-against-discretionary-investing/</guid><description>The reasons against discretionary investing 0. A financial asset&amp;rsquo;s price represents its concensus of its future, not just its present.
Eg. If you think Amazon will become more dominant in the future, and you have no insider information in your possession, you can bet that many others think the same, and using its past to extrapolate in to the future.
Its potential is already priced in by hundreds of thousands of participants in the market.</description></item></channel></rss>